{"tossups": [{"question": "This ship was captured by the USS<em> Washington</em> after Jose Ruiz and Pedro Montez secretly turned the ship north. Joseph Cinque was successful in taking over this ship, whose occupants of Mende [men-dee] descent revolted against Ramon Ferrer\u2019s crew and were held in New Haven, Connecticut during court proceedings. John Quincy Adams argued for the defendants in an 1841 case regarding, for the point, what Spanish ship that was the subject of a slave revolt near Cuba?", "answer": "La<b> Amistad</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "For the point, name this royal family that was founded by King Abdulaziz and rules from Riyadh.", "answer": "House of<b> Saud</b> (accept<b> Saud</b>i family)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "The Isla Gladstone Conservatory is in a park of this name that separates Goodison Park and Anfield, the home stadiums for the football teams Everton and Liverpool. A thousand-acre public park of this name in North America was built on land reclaimed from Chinese settlers near Vancouver. Both of those parks are named for an Earl of Derby who served as Governor General of Canada in the late 19th century and donated a silver rose bowl to serve as a Dominion Challenge Cup. For the point, give this name bestowed upon the trophy given annually to the champion of the National Hockey League.", "answer": "<b> Stanley</b> (accept<b> Stanley</b> Park; accept Frederick Arthur<b> Stanley</b>, Earl of Derby; accept <b>Stanley</b> Cup)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man referred to the War on Drugs as two wars, \u201cone abroad and one at home,\u201d and he lamented\u201cAmerica\u2019s health care system is neither healthy, caring, nor a system.\u201d A staffer said \u201cConnally too\u201dduring this man\u2019s reading of bulletin reports about the assassination of John F. Kennedy. Lyndon Johnson once said that if he lost this man, \u201c[he] lost Middle America.\u201d This man highlighted the objectivity of his reports with his signature phrase \u201cand that\u2019s the way it is.\u201d For the point, name this \u201cmost trusted man in America,\u201d a longtime CBS News anchor during the 1960s and 1970s.", "answer": "Walter Lee<b> Cronkite</b>, Jr.", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "During this battle, a captain demanded \u201cSink that brute! What does he there?\u201d when the<em> S\u00b4erieuse</em>, a frigate, tried to fill a gap in the line of battle; accounts differ on whether that command was given on James Saumarez\u2019s<em> Orion</em> or Thomas Foley\u2019s<em> Goliath</em>. Admiral Brueys [broo-ehz] was hit in the chest by a cannonball during this battle shortly before cans of paint fueled a fire that caused his flagship, the<em> Orient</em>, to explode. This August 1798 battle decided the Mediterranean campaign, a crucial loss for Napoleon. For the point, name this battle fought in Aboukir Bay near the delta of an Egyptian river.", "answer": "Battle of the<b> Nile</b> (accept Battle of<b> Aboukir</b> Bay before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "At one of these facilities in Kunming, members of a Uyghur [wee-gurr] separatist group stabbed and killed over 30 people in 2014. Almost 200 olive and cypress trees were planted in a memorial to a 2004 bombing at one of these facilities called Madrid Atocha. James Garfield was fatally shot in one of these facilities, the Baltimore and Potomac. The Gare du Nord is the busiest European example of, for the point, what type of infrastructure that often includes connections to buses and subways?", "answer": "<b> train station</b>s (accept equivalents; accept<b> subway station</b>s,<b> metro station</b>s, etc.)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "John Adams claimed that one man would \u201chave given 500 Guineas for a single vote\u201d at a meeting of this body that resulted in the issuing of a set of \u201cResolves,\u201d including the right to self-taxation. Members of this group secretly met at Raleigh Tavern during a series of extralegal meetings of this body presided over by Peyton Randolph. At the Second Convention of this body, the line \u201cGive me liberty, or give me death\u201d was delivered by Patrick Henry in the presence of statesmen like Thomas Jefferson. For the point, name this legislative assembly of colonial Virginia.", "answer": "<b> House of Burgesses</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In Norman England, the \u201cHue and Cry\u201d drafted everyday citizens into this profession via the Statute of Winchester. A group of 300 Scythian Slaves known as the \u201crod bearers\u201d served this purpose during meetings in ancient Athens. In London, author Henry Fielding led a group of these people known as the Bow Street Runners. Robert Peel\u2019s work establishing this profession in England led them to be called\u201cBobbies.\u201d For the point, name this profession that, in London, is based at Scotland Yard.", "answer": "<b> police</b> (accept elaborations and equivalents, like<b> constable</b>s)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "In 1931, a Jewish journalist and politician in this country named Shmuel Hayyim was executed for conspiracy to overthrow the monarchy. In this country, a man who called himself the \u201cGate\u201d was executed in 1850 for claiming to be the Mahdi. This country\u2019s government follows the principle of Guardianship of the Jurist, in which Islamic theologians wield government power. Baha\u2019i and a much older religion, Zoroastrianism, each originated in, for the point, what central Asian country whose current government is run by Ayatollah Khameini?", "answer": "<b> Iran</b> (or<b> Persia</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "While holding this position, Michael Bilandic mishandled a 1979 blizzard, paving the way for Jane Byrne to become the first woman in this post. The Council Wars involved the first African-American to hold this position, Harold Washington. A more recent holder of this position was heavily criticized for his handling of the shooting of Laquan McDonald and served as Chief of Staff under President Obama. Lori Lightfoot became the first openly LGBT person to hold, for the point, what position of leadership in Illinois?", "answer": "<b> mayor</b> of<b> Chicago</b> (prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "These places are called \u201ctotal institutions\u201d in a book by Erving Goffman. In a study performed by David Rosenhan, participants entered these places while pretending to hear the words \u201cempty,\u201d \u201chollow,\u201dand \u201cthud.\u201d Malpractice in one of these places on Blackwell\u2019s Island was exposed by Nellie Bly. Dorothea Dix campaigned for the creation of these places, where lobotomies and electric shocks were once used. For the point, name these institutions for the treatment of mental illnesses.", "answer": "<b> asylum</b> (accept<b> psychiatric ward</b>s; accept<b> mental hospital</b> before \u201cmental\u201d is read, and prompt on it after; prompt on \u201chospital\u201d or similar generic terms)", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Psychology"}, {"question": "The organizer of this movement claimed it would be carried out \u201cas gently as a breeze or a fine rain.\u201d This initiative began with a speech titled<em> On the Correct Handling of the Contradictions Among</em> <em>the People</em>. During this initiative, the \u201cDemocratic Wall\u201d was built by students in its nation\u2019s capital. The Anti-Rightist Movement arose during this campaign, which was halted after its leader heard of Khrushchev\u2019s denouncement of Stalin in the neighboring Soviet Union. For the point, name this initiative in which Mao opened his regime up to criticism in an attempt to allow the title objects to bloom.", "answer": "<b> Hundred Flowers</b> Campaign (accept<b> Baihua Qifang</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "For the point, name this monarch who led Germany into World War I.", "answer": "Kaiser<b> Wilhelm II</b> (or<b> William II</b>; prompt on Wilhelm or William)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A group of six composers who worked in this city included the composer of the Gaelic Symphony, Amy Beach. The first movement of a Charles Ives work that includes movements like \u201cPutnam\u2019s Camp\u201dis a tribute to a memorial in this city. Serge Koussevitzky and Seiji Ozawa directed this city\u2019s symphony orchestra, whose summer home is at Tanglewood. Keith Lockhart currently conducts an orchestra in this city that plays at the Hatch Shell every Fourth of July, this city\u2019s \u201cPops.\u201d For the point, name this capital, both musical and political, of Massachusetts.", "answer": "<b> Boston</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "After this artist rejected the gift of a peeled and sliced pineapple as a painting reference, the Dole company sent this artist to Hawaii in 1939 to paint an intact pineapple and images of hibiscus and ginger flowers for advertisements. This painter failed to complete a mural in the Radio City Music Hall\u2019s women\u2019s room, although her<em> Exotic Flowers</em> design was finished by another artist. This artist\u2019s home in New Mexico inspired<em> Cow\u2019s Skull: Red, White, and Blue</em> and her paintings of<em> Red Cannas</em>. For the point, name this 20th century American painter of sensual flowers.", "answer": "Georgia<b> O\u2019Keeffe</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This leader released Wilhelm Reinhard von Neipperg from prison to provide much needed military leadership; Neipperg promptly lost the Battle of Mollwitz. Great Britain demanded the abolition of the Ostend Company to recognize this leader\u2019s succession. This monarch, who allied with France to begin the Seven Years War, was the subject of Charles VI\u2019s Pragmatic Sanction and led Frederick the Great to invade Silesia, sparking the War of the Austrian Succession. For the point, name this Holy Roman Empress and last member of the Habsburg Dynasty.", "answer": "<b> Maria Theresa</b> Walburga Amalia Christina", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This politician would not \u201cgive the people false hope,\u201d earning the nickname \u201cTough Fighter\u201d for resisting demolishing the Queen\u2019s Pier. During an election, this leader used the slogan \u201cWe Care, We Listen, We Act.\u201d C.Y. Leung was replaced by this leader, who was criticized for supporting an extradition bill that would have potentially undermined the \u201cone country, two systems\u201d policy. For the point, name this first female Chief Executive in Hong Kong history.", "answer": "Carrie<b> Lam</b> (or<b> Lam</b> Cheng Yuet Ngor)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "Mayor George William Brown, the mayor of the city where this facility is located, was held prisoner here during the Civil War on suspicion of having Confederate sympathies. The first official 49-star and 50-star flags flew over the main building of this facility, which was named for a Secretary of War during the Washington and Adams administrations. George Armistead commanded this fort during its most famous action, which was observed from the HMS<em> Tonnant</em> by a lawyer conducting prisoner exchange. For the point, name this fort overlooking Baltimore Harbor whose bombardment by the British during the War of 1812 inspired the \u201cStar Spangled Banner.\u201d", "answer": "Fort<b> McHenry</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "For the point, name this 1967 Supreme Court case that ruled bans on interracial marriages to be unconstitutional.", "answer": "<b> Loving</b> v. Virginia", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In 1950, controversy erupted in this city after Maria Hertogh, whose parents were Catholic and who was raised by Muslims, was found praying to the Virgin Mary. This city was the site of a bomb explosion at a branch of HSBC at MacDonald House during the Konfrontasi. Many Chinese citizens were purged in this city by occupying Japanese soldiers in the 1942 Sook Ching massacre. Stamford Raffles founded and Lee Kuan Yew led, for the point, what Southeast Asian city at the tip of the Malay Peninsula?", "answer": "<b> Singapore</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Following the Civil War, the USS<em> Wachusett</em> was sent to this river to search for the CSS<em> Shenandoah</em>. Prior to one conflict, the<em> Jardine</em> was denied entrance to this river. During the Amethyst Incident, four Royal Navy ships ran aground in this river and came under fire from Communist forces. The First Opium War was ended by a treaty signed on a gunboat stationed on this river. Nanjing is on the delta of, for the point, what longest river in China?", "answer": "<b> Yangtze</b> River (accept<b> Chang Jiang</b>; accept<b> Da Jiang</b>; prompt on Long River or Great River)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "The earliest known example of the hierarchy of these beings is outlined by the 6th century thinker Pseudo-Dionysius in<em> On the Celestial Hierarchy</em>. The Epistle to the Hebrews claims that some people have entertained these beings without being aware of it. One of these beings announces to both Elizabeth and Mary that they will give birth. The Catholic Church only names Raphael, Michael, and Gabriel as, for the point, what holy beings from Christianity whose varieties include cherubs?", "answer": "<b> angel</b>s", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {"question": "This man was replaced by Lachlan Macquarie as governor of New South Wales during a rebellion in which he was deposed by Major George Johnston and John MacArthur. In 1787, this man led a Royal Society expedition to obtain breadfruit trees, but Fletcher Christian led an uprising against him after they left Tahiti. The Rum Rebellion was carried out against, for the point, what British naval officer who was set adrift after the mutiny on the<em> Bounty</em>?", "answer": "William<b> Bligh</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In the early 1990s, this school\u2019s quarterbacks included future Colorado Rockie Todd Helton, future Congressman Heath Shuler, and future quarterback Peyton Manning. This school won 16 SEC titles and 8 NCAA titles under Pat Summitt prior to Connecticut\u2019s domination of women\u2019s basketball. High military turnout in the War of 1812 inspired this school\u2019s mascot name. For the point, name this school where the Volunteers play in Knoxville.", "answer": "University of<b> Tennessee</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "This kingdom instituted the Jamabandi, a direct tax on the peasant class. A missionary from Goa was allowed to live in this kingdom by its ruler Hyder Ali. William Baillie\u2019s forces were defeated by this empire at the Battle of Pollilur partly due to its effective use of rockets. A thriving silk industry led this kingdom to have one of the highest standards of living under Tipu Sultan. The Maratha Confederacy assisted the British in a series of four wars against, for the point, what kingdom in southern India?", "answer": "Kingdom of<b> Mysore</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "During this event, Samuel Ward King requested aid from federal troops because many of his state militiamen supported the opposing side. The leader of this event considered including black men in his\u201cPeople\u2019s Constitution\u201d but was stopped by pressure from white immigrants. John Tyler declined to send federal troops to stop this uprising, which stemmed from a state\u2019s outdated 1663 colonial charter requiring ownership of $134 worth of property to vote. For the point, name this 1841 rebellion in Rhode Island.", "answer": "<b> Dorr</b>\u2019s Rebellion", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This author wrote<em> Come, Tell Me How You Live</em> about working on archaeological research with Max Mallowan. Experience as a VAD nurse in Torquay in World War I gave this author an understanding of poisons, which are used in her novels<em> The Mysterious Affair at Styles</em> and<em> And Then There Were None</em>. For the point, name this author who created the egg-headed Belgian detective Hercule Poirot and the English spinster detective Miss Marple, known as the English Queen of Crime.", "answer": "Dame Agatha<b> Christie</b> (accept Dame Agatha Mary Clarissa Miller<b> Christie</b>, DBE; accept Mary<b> Westmacott</b>; accept Lady<b> Mallowan</b> until \u201cMax Mallowan\u201d is mentioned, and prompt afterwards)", "metadata": "Literature - British Literature - Short Fiction"}, {"question": "This organization hired a Singaporean businessman named Amos Dawe in a failed attempt to buy three California banks. Maurice Dejean was blackmailed by this organization after it sent attractive women, known as \u201cswallows,\u201d to romance him. The Polish United Workers\u2019 Party thwarted attempts by this organization to undermine the Solidarity Movement. A hotel in the constituent republic of Estonia was bugged for twenty years by this organization, which was headquartered in Lubyanka Square. The NKVD and Cheka were replaced by, for the point, what \u201cCommittee for State Security\u201d in the Soviet Union?", "answer": "<b> KGB</b> (or<b> Komitet Gosudarstvennoy Bezopasnosti</b>; accept<b> Committee for State Security</b> before it is read)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A 2019 expos\u00b4e on the former CEO of this company noted that he planned to \u201csave the women of Saudi Arabia\u201d by offering coding classes and mentoring Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman. SoftBank\u2019s valuation of this company at $47 billion in December 2018 was meant to allow this company to go public, but it postponed its IPO in September 2019 amid concern that CEO and co-founder Adam Neumann had sold much of his equity. The \u201cunicorn bubble\u201d is said to have popped with the collapse of, for the point, what company that leases office buildings to serve as communal workspace?", "answer": "<b> WeWork</b> (accept The<b> We</b> Company)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "After being arrested for criticizing this action, Frank Key Howard wrote<em> Fourteen Months in American</em> <em>Bastilles</em>, after which two of his publishers were arrested. This action, which was carried out to prevent members of the Maryland General Assembly from voting to destroy railways, was ruled unconstitutional by Roger Taney in the 1861 case<em> Ex parte Merryman</em>. For the point, name this controversial action in which Abraham Lincoln suspended a writ allowing prisoners to demand to be brought before a judge.", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln\u2019s<b> suspension of habeas corpus</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Description acceptable. During this period, violent clashes like the Tapani Incident led one country to consider selling land to France. The Seediq people launched a widespread resistance to this period, causing the government to drop mustard gas over Musha in possibly the first use of chemical warfare in Asia. Shortly after this period began with the 1895 signing of the Treaty of Shimonoseki, the city of Tainan was invaded to crush the rebellious Republic of Formosa. For the point, name this period that began when China ceded an island governed from Taipei to a rising East Asian empire.", "answer": "<b> Japanese Taiwan</b> (accept answers relating to<b> Japan</b> controlling the island of<b> Taiwan</b>; accept<b> Japanese</b> control of<b> Formosa</b> before \u201cFormosa\u201d is read)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This position\u2019s first holder was the foster father of William Tecumseh Sherman and earlier served as Secretary of Treasury under John Tyler. Columbus Delano held this position under Ulysses Grant and organized an expedition under Ferdinand Hayden. Warren G. Harding persuaded Edwin Denby to grant his holdings to a holder of this position, who gave Harry Sinclair and Edward Doheny leases to drill for oil in the Black Hills. Albert Fall held, for the point, what Cabinet position responsible for federal land and natural resources?", "answer": "U.S. Secretary of the<b> Interior</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Mayors of this city in the 19th century included Robert Van Wyck, who resigned amid the American Ice scandal and served as its first post-consolidation mayor, and Fernando Wood, who supported the Confederacy and suggested that this city secede from the Union. Edward Cooper briefly led this city but is more famous as the son of a philanthropist who founded a free school here, Peter Cooper. A Depression-era mayor of this city names one of its airports and employed Robert Moses, who ensured that the headquarters of the United Nations was built here. For the point, name this city once led by Fiorello La Guardia.", "answer": "<b> New York</b> City (or<b> NY</b>C)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "In 59 BC, Publius Clodius Pulcher gained this position despite dubious eligibility and passed laws to exile Cicero and distribute free grain to the poor. Sulla removed this office\u2019s powers to initiate legislation and to veto acts of the Senate. This office had been established in 494 BC after a rebellion of the lower social orders. For the point, name this office of the ancient Roman Republic that was designed as a check on patrician power on behalf of the plebeians.", "answer": "<b> tribune</b>s of the people (or<b> tribune</b>s of the plebeians)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "People with this profession storm into the wedding of Marie and Tonio in a Gaetano Donizetti opera. A chorus of people with this profession sing \u201cGlory and love to the men of old\u201d in Charles Gounod\u2019s<em> Faust</em>. A character with this profession fights the bullfighter Escamillo in an opera in which he stabs the title gypsy girl. For the point, name this profession of Don Jose in Carmen and by characters in<em> The Daughter</em> <em>of the Regiment</em> who fight in the Napoleonic Wars.", "answer": "<b> soldier</b>s (accept equivalents)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Opera"}, {"question": "This man\u2019s great-grandson with the same name carried out an ill-fated air raid on Kiel, becoming the first American general to be killed in World War II. A raid on Memphis in 1864 was carried out by this general, who defeated Samuel Sturgis at Brice\u2019s Cross Roads. At Fort Donelson, this man led forces to break out against Ulysses Grant. An 1867 meeting at the Maxwell House Hotel in Nashville promoted, for the point, what \u201cWizard of the Saddle,\u201d a Confederate general from Tennessee, to become the first Grand Wizard of the KKK?", "answer": "Nathan Bedford<b> Forrest</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "In this war, Huey Long had a fort named after him because he denounced Standard Oil\u2019s involvement in it. During this war, Daniel Salamanca dismissed General Hans Kundt, whose losses included the Battle of Nanawa. This war was fought over a region bounded to the south by the Picomayo River. Troops of Quechua descent suffered extreme thirst in this war, while their Guarani counterparts fared better. For the point, name this 1932 to 1935 South American war in which Paraguay fought Bolivia over oil reserves in a namesake region.", "answer": "Gran<b> Chaco</b> War", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This The Marquis de Louvois helped increase this ruler\u2019s army, which destroyed Brussels in 1695. This ruler\u2019s admiral, the Comte de Tourville, won the Battle of Beachy Head against the Dutch and English in the Nine Years\u201d War. By placing a Bourbon on the throne of Spain, this man began the War of the Spanish Succession. Jean-Baptiste Colbert served this king, who revoked the Edict of Nantes with the Edict of Fontainebleau, causing many Huguenots to leave France. For the point, name this absolutist Sun King.", "answer": "<b> Louis XIV</b> [14] (prompt on \u201cSun King\u201d before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "On this island, the ambush of the Four Four Bravo patrol sparked the Black July riots against an ethnic group on the Jaffna Peninsula. After the Battle of Kilinochchi on this island, Velupillai Prabhakaran was reported dead, ending a 26-year-long civil war. A 1998 suicide bombing on this island damaged the Temple of the Tooth in its city of Kandy. The militant Tamil Tigers fought against the Sinhalese population of, for the point, what island off the southern coast of India?", "answer": "<b> Sri Lanka</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This newspaper was sold at a 1933 bankruptcy auction to Eugene Myer. One editor of this newspaper published a book of<em> Conversations With Kennedy</em>.<em> The New York Times</em> and this paper were parties in a combined 1971 Supreme Court case regarding the right to publish the Pentagon Papers. The statement\u201cDemocracy dies in darkness\u201d is the slogan of this paper, which employed Carl Bernstein and Bob Woodward, the authors of<em> All the President\u2019s Men</em>, during the Watergate scandal. For the point, name this daily newspaper headquartered in D.C.", "answer": "The<b> Washington Post</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This philosopher\u2019s<em> Sophistical Refutations</em> was his earliest book on deduction, while the<em> Prior</em> and <em>Posterior Analytics</em> are syllogistic works of logic by this philosopher. In his best known book of ethics, this philosopher claimed that virtue was the mean between two vices. The<em> Physics</em> and<em> Metaphysics</em> were written by, for the point, what Greek philosopher, the tutor of Alexander the Great and student of Plato?", "answer": "<b> Aristotle</b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "Roscoe Hillenkoetter was the first head of this organization, which was accused of influencing a 1948 Italian election in favor of the Christian Democrats. With the help of Kermit Roosevelt, a leader of this organization helped carry out Operation Ajax, which overthrew Mohammad Mosaddegh as leader of Iran. Allen Dulles once led this organization, which was created after the passage of the 1947 National Security Act. Several anti-communist coups were organized by, for the point, what American agency responsible for gathering international intelligence?", "answer": "<b> Central Intelligence Agency</b> (or<b> CIA</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The temple of Nyserre Ini at Abusir was dedicated to this object, which is depicted at many temples in the Middle East with wings. This object was depicted with a snake in the uraeus symbol. A boat representing this object was defended by Set from the serpent Apep; that boat was owned by a god who was the king of the Egyptian pantheon and worshiped in Heliopolis. For the point, name this celestial object represented by Ra in ancient Egypt.", "answer": "the<b> Sun</b>", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {"question": "Arbegnoch, the Amharic word for this English term, names an Ethiopian resistance movement that fought Italian invaders in the 1930s. In the late 1700s, a group with this name opposed the Orangists and stadtholder William V in the Netherlands. A Quebecois group of this name fought a namesake war as part of the 1837-38 Rebellions in Canada. In pre-revolution America, many of these people aligned with the British Whigs and \u201cNo Taxation without Representation.\u201d For the point, give this term for American colonists who supported independence from Britain, as opposed to the Loyalists.", "answer": "<b> Patriot</b>s", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This civilization\u2019s artwork includes the Chimera of Arezzo, which depicts the title beast fighting the hero Bellerophon. As dictator, Camillus led a plebiscite army against these people that used siege tunnels against the city of Veii. A league of these people allied with the southern city of Capua to oppose the spread of Roman influence. For the point, name this ancient civilization of northern and central Italy that lends its name to the modern region of Tuscany.", "answer": "<b> Etruscan</b>s", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}